# ZOE GENEVIEVE LEBLANC

HISTORIAN & DEVELOPER

# **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

I'm currently completing my doctorate in history at Vanderbilt University and recently completed the Nashville Software School Software Developer Bootcamp. I'm interested in opportunities where I can further my knowledge of software development, contribute to digital humanities projects, and collaborate with a team. I'm particularly passionate about developing new methods for researchers to create and share knowledge.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Data Developer, Aspire Health, 03/2017-Present

Responsible for building internal data analysis applications and normalizing data structures. Worked with both development and data science teams to increase patient enrollment.

# Teaching Assistant, Department of History, Vanderbilt University, 09/2012-05/2015

Taught undergraduate courses on American, Middle East, and Global history. Responsible for classroom management and lesson plan development. Learned communication, writing, and research management skills.

# Web Designer and Office Manager, Contemporary Computers, 12/2010-08/2011

Designed business plan and websites for computer repair store. Learned foundations of computer hardware and website design.

# **SELECTED PROJECTS**

# Image Lucida, 2017-Pesent

Image annotation and analysis web app built to help researchers analyze and extract large image datasets. Beta-testing on dissertation research. View: www.github.com/ZoeLeBlanc/image\_lucida

# Archivlo, 2016-Present

Archival research workflow web app. Connects researchers in archives, and helps them build and share research projects. View: www.github.com/ZoeLeBlanc/archivlo

# Digital Humanities Projects from Dissertation, 2016-Present

Two projects: "Dispatches from Cairo" a text analysis project of Western diplomatic dispatches from Cairo and "Depictions of Decolonization" an image analysis project of anti-colonial newspapers and magazines. View: www.zoeleblanc.com/projects/

### Constructing Anti-Colonial Cairo, 2014-Present

Dissertation on the history of global anti-colonialism in the 1950s and 60s through analysis of print media from Cairo, Egypt. Utilizes archival data from multiple countries and languages. More info: www.zoeleblanc.com/projects/dissertation/

# **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. in History, Vanderbilt University, 05/2014- Present

M.A. in History, Vanderbilt University, 09/2011-04/2014

Honours Bachelor of Arts with High Distinction, Trinity College, University of Toronto, 09/2006-06/2010

zgleblanc@gmail.com zoeleblanc.com 615.810.6485 Nashville, TN

# SOCIAL

TWITTER/ Zoe\_LeBlanc

GITHUB/ ZoeLeBlanc

in LINKEDIN/ in/zoe-leblanc

O INSTAGRAM/ zoe-genevieve

# **SKILLS**

#### Experienced:

Web app development, project management, data analysis, Agile, and Unit Testing. HTML, CSS, Sass, Javascript, JQuery, Angular, Python, Django, SQL, Git, Grunt, Browserify, Firebase.

Beginner - Intermediate: Data visualization, mapping, networks analysis, and U/X. R, React, Redux, Immutable.js, Thunk, D3.js, Mocha, Chai, Elixir, Postgres, T-SQL, Vim

Fluent in French, advanced reading and writing in Arabic

# SELECTED AWARDS

Vanderbilt Digital Humanities Fellowship, 2016-2017

Canadian Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council Dissertation Award, 2014-2016

Nashville Software School Tuition Scholarship & Catalyst Award 2017

Vanderbilt Institute of Digital Learning Graduate Fellowship, 2014-2015

HASTAC Scholar, Vanderbilt Center for Teaching, 2012-2013

Vanderbilt Graduate Fellowship, 2011-2017